S. ASAD ABBAS ZAIDI

+91 9919 7411 45 asad.asad.abbas@gmail.com Buniyad Bagh, Saadatganj, Lucknow.



SUMMARY

Co-founder and **Director** of a service based company in India | Lead a team of 10 members over 3 years and have a total experience of 9+ years | Well-versed in C#, ASP.Net, Ruby on Rails, Flutter, Angular, SQL Server, Jquery and ADO.Net. Strong background in management and leadership | Clients included Tier-1 from India and across the globe (UK, USA)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages	Frameworks	Databases	Web Platform	Tools/Cloud
♦ HTML/CSS	◆ .Net, ADO.Net	◆ SQLServer	◆ HubSpot	◆ TortoiseGit
◆ Javascript	◆ Entity Framework, WCF	◆ MySQL	◆ ParseHub	◆ Github/Gitlab
◆ C#	◆ Rails◆ Flutter◆ Angular	◆ PostgreSQL		◆ AWS CLI, RDS, EC2, S3
◆ XML	◆ Node.Js, Loopback.Js	◆ Cosmos DB		◆ JIRA
◆ Ruby	◆ Android			

EDUCATION

◆ Lucknow Institute of Technology, Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh — Bachelor of Technology (CSE), 2011-2015.

Obtained — 74%

◆ City Montessori School, Rajendra Nagar, Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh — Intermediate (PCM, ISC), 2011.

Obtained — 72%

◆ City Montessori School, Rajendra Nagar, Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh — Intermediate (PCM, ICSE), 2009.

Obtained — 86.3%

EXPERIENCE

Company	Designation	Working Period
Company 1	Co-founder, Director, Senior Software Developer & Manager	2017-present
Company 2	Software Developer	2015-2017

PROJECTS

◆ Task and Time Management system (Product: Asp.Net, SQLServer, Angular) (CURRENT)

Role: Manager, Developer

◆ VIN Tracking (Project: Asp.Net, SQLServer)

Role: Lead Developer and Manager

- Lead developer on the project and had built it from scratch
- VIN tracking was done where the VIN details were entered manually into the system and thereafter levels of process were carried out to further move the VIN.
- Client requirement was also to extract the VIN details from a server by parsing the XML file available.
- API for mobile end was also developed.
- ◆ Audit Report System (Project: Asp.Net, SQLServer)

Role: Lead Developer and Manager

- Lead developer on the project and had built it from scratch
- Web Auditing system to manage audits on the basis of questions that were managed by the admin.
- API for mobile end was also developed.
- ◆ Automobile Portal (Project: Ruby on Rails, MySQL) (CURRENT)

Role: Lead Developer and Manager

- This was handed over from an existing developer but it required major theme revamp.
- Notifications using rPush was integrated into the system
- APIs were also managed alongwith a requirement where similar sets of responses need to be generated for a different sub-product used by the same client.
- ◆ Event Web Portal (Project: Ruby on Rails, MySQL)

Role: Team Member

- Manage events from unstructured and structured websites and consolidate all the duplicate events into one.
- Manage brands and retailers and provide them the best matched events on the basis of their business objectives and event categories.
- ◆ E-Commerce API (Project: Loopback.Js, MySQL)

Role: Team Member

- Shopping cart application with wardrobe availability

- Register, login and basic CRUD operations
- Product management and Admin Panel API
- Filter API's into the product panel.

◆ Server Management

 For a duration of 6 months have provided support on AWS to a company involving disk cleanup, EC2 deployment, URL redirection through config changes, RDS scaling, CLI troubleshooting.

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

- ◆ ADCA certification from CICET, Lucknow
- ◆ 4 weeks summer training on Networking in RTTC BSNL, Lucknow
- ◆ 3 months training on ASP.NET MVC 5 at Tech Fame, Lucknow